When they put their heads together... it's a no brainer.
Lucky Numbers is a comedy, crime film directed by Nora Ephron.
Russ Richards is a TV weatherman and local celebrity
on the verge of losing his shirt.
Desperate to escape financial ruin, he schemes with Crystal the TV
station's lotto ball girl to rig the state lottery drawing.
The numbers come up right, but everything else goes wrong as the
plan starts to unravel and the game turns rough.
Russ Richards, played by John Travolta.
Crystal, played by Lisa Kudrow.
Gig, played by Tim Roth.
Dick Simmons, played by Ed O'Neill.
Dale, played by Michael Rapaport.
Detective Chambers, played by Daryl Mitchell.
Lucky Numbers is a 2000 black comedy film directed by Nora Ephron.
It stars John Travolta, Lisa Kudrow, Tim Roth, Ed O'Neill, Michael Rapaport,  Richard
Schiff, Daryl Mitchell, Bill Pullman, and Michael Moore in a rare acting role.
The screenplay by Adam Resnick was inspired by the
1980 Pennsylvania Lottery scandal.
It is the only film Ephron directed without also writing the screenplay.
Lucky Numbers was released on October 27, 2000 by Paramount Pictures in international
markets, BAC Films in France and StudioCanal in Europe and Africa.
The film received negative reviews and was a box-office bomb,
grossing $10.9 million against a $63 million budget.
The film explores themes of weather forecast,
lottery, weather forecaster, weather, debt.
The tone is lighthearted.